We don't need another political fight.
We need a matriarchal ship.
Now, let's be clear.
When these folks say this,
they're not talking about you
just because you're classified as a woman.
Having a vagine and or a uterus,
yeah, that doesn't make you a matriarch.
We know full well that there have been many women
that have been upholding
and letting patriarchy suck from the boob, okay?
This has been happening across race, class, gender,
across the globe.
So I just wanna specify that
because folks will think,
well, I'm sitting at home knitting a pussy hat.
So like I'm a part of the matriarchal shift
and you are not.
You are not.
All you feminists who don't understand intersectionalism,
you are actually not a part of the matriarchal shift.
The matriarchal shift understands this.
At the core of matriarchy is life.
You see, what we've got here is a flower.
At the top, we've got love,
we've got regeneration,
we've got reciprocity,
and we've got community.
You know what the best part of matriarchy is?
You don't have to be a woman to honor it.
You don't have to be a woman to uplift it.
You don't have to be a woman to be matriarchal.
What you are is someone who respects
and who understands that community,
regeneration, love, and reciprocity
are how the earth will thrive
and how we of the earth will thrive.
Thank you for attending today's Amanda Talk.
Ba-jum-bam!